Alexander Carlson

Freelance Web Developer

Address Chicago, IL, 60608 LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/alex-carlson-

Phone (815) 531-9682 53b1439a/

E-mail araycarlson@gmail.com WWW alexandercarlson.com

Ambitious, goal oriented Full Stack Developer brings problem-solving and powerful technology skills to web development process. Innate ability to communicate across teams to design interface that accommodates specifications. Brings background in graphic arts, coding, media integration and SEO to accomplish tasks. Committed to high standards of user experience, usability and speed.

Skills

Front End Developent: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, React,

Bootstrap

RESTful services (Create/Read/Update/Delete with

AJAX/JSON)

Relational Database Modeling: SQL/MySQL, MongoDB,

Express, Node

Software Best Practices

Work History

2020-05 - Current

Freelance Web Developer

Self Employed, Chicago, IL

- Planned and developed interfaces using HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, and React.js that simplified overall management and offered ease-of-use.
- Contributed ideas and suggestions in team meetings and delivered updates on deadlines, designs and enhancements.
- Wrote MERN Stack (MongoDB, Express, React, Node.js) applications for the ecommerce industry.
- Designed, developed and implemented software applications for website based on analyzed requirements and understanding of industry technical standards.
- · Employed Git and GitHub for version control management

2019-02 - 2020-04

Software Engineer

Closed Brackets, Colorado Springs, CO

- Designed, implemented and monitored web pages, plugins and functionality for continuous improvement.
- Researched, designed and implemented scalable applications for information identification, extraction, analysis, retrieval and indexing.
- Oversaw web platform testing, troubleshooting and user sampling prior to live deployment.
- Established presentation consistency across Chrome, Safari, Firefox and other common browser interfaces.
- · Developed Full Stack MERN applications for fitness and ecommerce industries.
- Interfaced between high-value customers and utilized client feedback in software updates.
- · Maintained version control in collaboration with engineering team (Git and GitHub)

Education

2020-05 - 2020-10 Certificate of Completion: Javascript Development

General Assembly - Remote (Online)

2007-08 - 2011-12 Bachelor of Arts: Fine Arts (Painting)

Illinois State University - Normal, IL